yeah uh so as I said we'll be starting
off uh with the topic which is uh test
case designing with trien
tosa now uh there are lots of different
topics within this uh one topic and U it
is one of the core framework uh you can
say within which tosa works so
everything can be linked to the test
case designing and uh it is the point
where uh you can start your testing or
automation testing within
tosa now uh this is the part which is
most important and also I find uh the
most confusing when you are new to tosa
I have seen people uh not able to
understand and uh hence um some teams
also skip uh the test case designing and
they start um directly using the test
cases section and
execution but then you are not utilizing
uh the core framework of tosa um which
helps you to basically uh design test
cases in the most efficient manner and
then also it helps you to um maximize uh
the coverage of your test cases and also
it minimizes the risk uh because you are
having the maximum coverage with the
optimum number of test cases which is uh
like a core concept of any testing right
so before we go and understand how it
works in tosa uh we need to also
understand uh where is this coming from
right so tosa has implemented this
within the tool but uh the logic is uh
coming from um a functional testing
background so I don't know if you have
worked uh in functional or manual
testing but uh there are different test
case design techniques which um are are
always used whenever we start any
testing any functional or manual testing
and we start thinking about the
scenarios uh which we should be
developing or um how we should be
creating our test cases and how many
test cases are required to cover a
particular scenario so these design
techniques uh are used uh to find the
optimum number of test cases or the
minimum number of test cases which uh
needs to be developed in order to uh
cover all all parts of the application
which you're trying to test and with the
minimum number of test cases the reason
is pretty simple uh you don't have
enough time to test the complete
application and uh in that minimum
amount of time and since everybody is
nowadays working uh in the agile model
right so uh we have got this Sprints
which are bi-weekly or weekly and there
is minimum amount of time to um test a
particular application or test a
specific number of stories so in this
amount of time if you're trying to
automate and then you're trying to
execute and then you are trying to
determine whether your uh release should
go ahead or not based on the results
then you can imagine what amount of time
you have to test any particular
functionality um and leave if you have
got to test the whole application think
how much amount of time and uh can you
test the whole application with all sets
of test data so practically it is not
possible even uh the application which I
am currently looking on which is a demo
application by TOS by trentis so testing
this whole application testing all sets
of data uh for each field um if you have
got say three to four days uh it would
be impossible and that is the reason
test case design section is so important
so that you can generate those test
cases uh automatically first based on
some design technique and then you can
have the optimum number of test cases
which can give you the maximum coverage
and which can cover all the major risky
part of the application so that uh no
major issues are missed in your testing
right so this is where the whole
background is now coming to uh the
different techniques I was talking
about so one of the tech um or they are
combination of two techniques uh one is
called uh the equivalence partitioning
and then one is called the boundary
value analysis okay so both are interl
together and U I don't know if you have
heard about them but these are the two
techniques which are very popular while
uh you are designing test cases or you
are trying to um get the minimum number
of test cases which are required for a
particular scenario or you have got some
test data from which you want to derive
some test cases right so let me give you
an example and then we will try to
understand uh from a generic perspective
and then we will also see um how it can
be done in tosa how tosa utilizes these
uh Tech techniques and it has integrated
it into the test case designing section
right so in this uh particular page
which is the vehicle insurance
application which you see here okay so
you can see there are different fields
and then when we test this application
we will be I mean we should be testing
with different values for each field
right so for example uh if I test this
engine performance if I'm want to test
the value vales which are accepted here
and uh you can see it is a mandatory
field so obviously we need to test this
but what about uh the values right so
1200 you can see uh it is saying it is
valid but if I put another zero you will
see a warning comes up saying that uh
number must be between 1 and 2,000 right
so you can see there is a range uh
within which uh this particular field
accepts um accepts the number right so
this could be based on um any particular
business requirement so the requirement
is that the number must be between one
and 2,000 and as a tester it is your job
to make sure that you are testing all
the possible values uh for this
particular field right now uh if you
think that you can test all the 2,000 uh
numbers which are possible which is
between 1 and 2,000 so you need to enter
um all the 2,000 numbers and then you
need to create test cases which can test
all the uh values between this range
right which is practically impossible so
think this is for one field and then you
have got so many fields which have got
their own conditions own requirements so
rather than doing that uh you have to U
use the equivalence partitioning and the
boundary value analysis right uh so how
you will use
this so let's uh look with the help of
an
example okay so let's try and use this
and we will see so our values are
between um 1 and 2,000 right
so if uh the starting value is uh
somewhere around 1 and uh the ending
value is 2,000 then uh we can maybe
divide it into partitions
right so if I have got partitions like
this okay so these are the partitions so
how the partition will look like so this
is uh the valid partition which is 1 to
2000 and then uh this will be a
partition which will be greater than a
value which is
2,000 right and then this will be value
which will be uh less than one
okay uh so these are like three
partitions uh which we have divided our
values into and this is the concept
which is called equivalence partitioning
where you divide uh your values or your
data in different partitions and then
you pick um values from each partition
okay so what will happen is um I will
pick a one value from this particular
partition so which is less than one so
maybe a value of zero then I'll pick
some values between 1 and 2,000 1 to
2,000 so it could be something like 200
here and then I will pick uh some value
which is greater than 2,000 okay so
maybe uh
2500 now the reason for picking up uh
values in different partitions is uh the
concept where if one value like 200
Works in a particular partition you can
expect all the other values to work uh
also in that same partition so if I pick
200 or 500 or th000 we expect that if
200 is working then the other numbers
will also work and that is why we just
pick either maybe uh two to three
numbers at Max between each partition so
that we can test each of these
partitions which could um uh which which
could come up with different results
right and also what happens is um there
are maximum chances of some error
happening in your application in these
particular
partitions but still uh there is also
another scenario where um you have to
also test the boundaries of these
partitions okay so these are your
boundaries uh these lines are your
boundaries so there are you can see
there are two boundaries here so we need
to test the specific boundary values and
that is called the boundary value
analysis again okay so we have to test
uh a value like 2,000 and then something
like um 1,00 which is close to the
partition so you need to pick up some
values which are close to this
particular partition okay so one would
be less than 21 would be greater than
2,000 so that will test the boundary
values of this particular partition and
then for this particular uh boundary
values for this partition you can test
with again um a value Which is less
maybe zero and then you can also test
with a value two okay so these are like
the boundary values uh which will test
um the boundaries of each partition and
the reason for this is uh maximum
chances of any uh errors or any uh
coding errors which happen generally in
these boundary values and that is why it
is very important to test these boundary
values whenever you are uh trying to
design your test
scenarios now uh this was the manual
concept of uh the equivalence
partitioning and Boundary value analysis
uh when you design your test cases
manually right so we do this we divide
uh the values and then we derive our
test cases based on these particular
values and pretty much the same similar
concept has been um taken up by
tricentis and it has been integrated
into tosa now there are different uh
ways of how that has been designed uh
but we'll look at it okay so in this
session I'll use this particular uh
example we'll be trying to design a test
case for enter vehicle
data okay um so coming back to tosa uh
this is our tosa commander and um I have
created one component folder for today
and uh inside that component folder I
have got all my um different sections
you can see
here so we'll be working with the test
case designing
section and uh this is the test cage
designing
section so in test cage designing
section um we have the
core testing structure which is or the
basic framework which consists of test
sheets okay so test sheet inside the
test case design section in tosa forms
the basic framework through which you
can design your test cases now it looks
very similar to an Excel sheet it has
got different rows and columns uh but uh
tosa inside the test sheet uh it also
provides you options with attributes and
instances which you can link to your uh
business objects in your application and
then you can create different values for
those attributes and that is the way you
can design a particular test case
okay so um generally in a test case
design you first create a folder okay so
I create a folder
here and I name it something and then
inside this uh we create our test sheet
okay so this is the test sheet and then
uh you can have uh multiple test sheets
inside a folder uh generally for one
particular requirement you should have
one test sheet that is the best practice
but uh it depends on your requirement
how you want to um or how many number of
test sheets you want to have and how you
want to design your test cases
right so I'm going to call this a
vehicle
data and then inside the test sheet uh
once we create our test sheets uh we
have got as I said the option of
attributes so that's again the basic
basis of how you design your uh test
scenarios from your application so to
create attribute you have to right click
on the test sheet there will be an
option to create attribute and also
every attribute can have sub attributes
and then every attribute can have
instances okay
so to create a attribute uh you need to
right click and then um you can create
attribute you can create multiple
attributes and subattributes now first
understand uh how these attributes are
linked uh to your application how do you
design this right so if I look at this
uh particular application right so I can
have multiple attributes and this will
nothing these are nothing but these are
my business objects or you can think of
features which you're testing in your
application or it could be
functionalities or it could be um simple
Fields also you can convert your Fields
uh into attributes okay so you have to
think from a perspective like what do I
need in terms of testing this particular
application okay what I will be testing
right so in this particular page I want
to test uh enter vehicle data and then I
want to test all these different fields
have the correct values or when I'm
entering the values they are validated
and then I move on to the next screen
right so all these are my business
objects and these business objects are
represented as attributes and tosa okay
now in this particular application I can
have uh as I said multiple attributes I
can have attribute for enter vehicle
data for enter Insurance data enter
product data uh and then price option
right because every screen has got its
own Fields right so I want to group my
attributes accordingly so that I while
designing I can then map these
attributes to different instances which
are nothing but these values okay so
every field has got some uh particular
values or a range of values and these uh
range of values you can now convert it
into into instances so instances in test
case designing is nothing but your uh
different sets of values which are
possible for your attributes okay so so
these can be converted or you can think
these like the values for your different
fields in your application so this is
how you will design your test uh sheet
when you create it you look at your
application you decide what can become
an attribute and what can become an
instance
okay so here as I said um I can create
here enter or I can say yeah enter
vehicle data that is my first
attribute and inside this then I will
have multiple attributes like make
engine
performance uh Etc
right now there are multiple ways of
also creating attributes okay so you can
create attribute manually or uh you can
also create attributes from your module
attributes okay so I have already
scanned this particular page and I have
got these different attributes here uh
or module attributes as you can see so
these are nothing but uh my elements on
the page for this particular module
enter vehicle data right so if um I want
to create attributes from here okay so
that uh I can also do I can also uh
create this whole test sheet from an
external sheet like an Excel sheet if
you are maintaining that uh your
complete Fields you can create the
structure in the Excel sheet and then um
you can just uh extract that particular
uh instance and uh complete it from your
external sheet into this particular
sheet okay so that can also be
done there is an option for
that okay so create element from
clipboard so once you copy the structure
from the Excel sheet you can choose this
option uh and it will create the whole
structure in here or you can also create
the instances from the clipboard so
whatever you copy you can paste it here
but uh it has to be in a particular
structure which it can
accept Okay so uh as I said we can
create multiple attributes so I will
create some of them not all
here and then uh these will have
different values okay uh which are
nothing but your
instances so if I have got uh instance
for my make so you can see there are
different values here right OD BMW
Ford
so I can have uh different instances
here and then for engine performance we
discussed right so we we can have
different range of values uh we
discussed about the boundary values
which we want to test so um I will have
have a value like one here and then a
value
like uh
2,000 and a value like 12,000 which is a
invalid value now the reason for having
invalid values is you don't just want to
test the positive scenarios you also
want to test your negative scenarios and
that can be done with these instance
values which are um not valid instances
they are invalid instances right and
there is a way of categorize
categorizing the instances uh in tosa
and also you can um categorize your
attributes okay so there are different
categories which you can put for your
attributes and uh these are also uh
called the business uh relevance okay so
if you select any particular
attribute and you go to properties uh
and properties you will see a property
which is called business
relevant and uh it has got three values
uh yes no or result
okay uh now this categorization uh you
need to decide which attributes are
business relevant and which are not
business relevant a simple way to do
that is if I come here I can see there
are mandatory Fields And there are
non-mandatory Fields something like
a license plate number right so if I add
this if I create an attribute for
license plate number so both this make
and engine performance are mandatory
Fields so I would consider them as a
business relevant um attribute right so
this business relevance is basically um
which fields are relevant for your
business which carry more risk and which
are important and used uh by your
customers right so you make them
business relevance so that when you are
creating those uh test cases then you
will focus on these particular instances
but uh sometimes you may also require
some attributes which are not uh pretty
business relevance uh so but you still
want to test them and even if they fail
you can still consider them later on you
don't want to stop your release because
this business are not so business
relevant scenarios are not working but
you have to focus on your business
relevant scenarios right so you have to
differentiate between these different
attributes and that is what tosa um
allows you to do so in the test case
design section once you select any
particular attribute obviously you can
change it directly from the properties
here uh any particular value or uh you
can do is you can use the toggle
business relevance that is
uh shortcut as well so once you click on
this uh you will see that um the color
of this uh hul sign changes and now you
can see the business relevant is result
then if I toggle again it will become um
business relevant no which means it is
not business relevant and then if I
toggle again you it will see uh business
relevant set to yes which means um it is
a business relevant attribute right so
there are three different uh possible
values one is yes which means it is
business relevant one is no which is
which means it's not business relevant
and one is uh result so if I'm expecting
uh some result or if I want to verify
something in this particular field then
I can uh make this as a uh business
relevant equals to result okay so which
means I'm trying to validate something
here okay so this is the categorization
which you have to follow and for license
plate number we discussed uh we want to
put it as no so that it is not a
business relevant attribute so these are
the three categories you can see first
is uh business relevant uh then second
is result and third is not business
relevant okay so these are uh the three
properties which you can change in
attributes now uh coming to instances uh
there you will have the option to use uh
what we said the techniques which we
discussed the boundary value analysis
right so there uh tosa has provided some
options where you can work out and uh
decide which instances are boundary
values or which are not and then while
designing they will be considered also
okay uh while generating the
instances so if I go to any particular
instance like this is so when you select
any particular instance uh then you get
two
properties one is called the character
uh one is called the position okay so
using these two properties uh you can
basically decide uh which are valid
instances which are not valid or which
are within the boundary or which are not
within the boundary okay or which are
just at the boundary values so for
character we have got three different
options valid invalid and straight
through and then for position we have
got two values inner and Boundary okay
so uh if you think that this is the
boundary value then you set it uh to
boundary value if you think uh it is a
inner value which means it is within the
boundary range then you set it as inner
of for the position property for
character uh that is valid valid and
straight through so valid is pretty
straightforward you think it is a valid
uh instance where you don't expect any
errors then you put it as valid if you
think it is invalid and you expect an
error so you validate that it is
throwing a particular error message when
you select this particular instance then
you put it as invalid straight through
is something which uh is uh using the
minimum um number of uh combinations uh
it helps you to basically design optimum
number of test cases and also straight
through scenario is something like it is
used mostly by your customers and uh it
is a straight flow which is using the
less number of combinations in your
application and also it carries the
highest risk okay so a straight through
scenario for my this application would
be that I select the default value
like uh I select something like AI here
and then I select uh something like four
number of seats which is pretty common
in all the cars or all the vehicles
right so these are all the then I select
petrol here in fuel type so these are
all the straightforward values and these
are the values which are mostly used by
the customers when you they are trying
to use this particular application so
these values you will consider them as
the straight through values and you
enter them and the application should
behave as expected always right so
whenever you are designing your test
scenarios the state through instances
will carry the most um you can say
weightage when you are linking to your
requirements and also they should always
have the highest importance when you are
looking at your execution results okay
so that's that's the point of having
this state through
instances so as I said uh every
attribute should have one straight
through instance and it is also helpful
when you are trying to create instances
we'll see that okay um so if I consider
this as a straight through instance um
then this one I can say uh it is a valid
instance here coming to engine
performance right so uh one and 2,000 so
this is a valid instance this is also
valid uh this is a not valid instance
right and we will put this 2000 as a
straight through instance so you can see
all three categories right here uh and
then position right so 2001 is at the
boundary right so we consider this as a
boundary uh instance and then this is
also a boundary but since it is a
straight through character so position
is automatically set to Inner okay so
remember that whenever you set the
character a straight through by default
it becomes uh or the position is by
default inner you cannot change it it is
a readon uh value which is set by tosa
itself okay so we cannot change that and
then this character is invalid uh it uh
doesn't matter uh it will not be a
boundary value so we'll put it as inner
here okay so these are the different uh
properties which can be changed uh when
you are um putting your instances and
it's very important that you change this
properties for both attributes and
instances it helps you while you try to
instantiate or you create instances of
your um of your attributes uh which will
basically become your test scenarios
right so until now we have just created
you can see attributes and instances so
that it replicates um our behavior of
our business objects in our application
but uh still now we don't have any
instances for our test cases okay and
that can be done using uh or creating
instances for your test sheet so for
vehicle data we can also create
instances here directly and this will be
nothing but um it will be our test cases
so if I have got three different test
cases I or scenarios I want to test I
will create uh three test case instances
here okay and then you will see that it
will be converted into columns in our
test sheet until now we had only rows
but now we have got our actual test
cases which will be displayed as columns
okay so these are three different test
cases here and then um we can have
different sets of data for testing these
three different scenarios So based on
your requirements now you can design
your test cases uh with different sets
of values okay you don't want to test
with all the same set of values right so
here then we need to fill the values for
our test cases okay so all the instances
or all the attributes will have some
value okay and these values will be
picked from these instances so you need
to make sure that your test sheet uh or
your test sheet instances have got um
the values because this will drive your
test case Okay so if I'm selecting some
value in make so what it will do it will
go into the application and then it will
select this particular value similarly
for all the other fields
so here uh we will select any particular
value uh say we are selecting a state
through instance for all the different
values okay and here I can enter
something uh similarly for here uh we
will select some other
value and then here uh um we will select
some other
value okay maybe a invalid scenario we
are testing
here so you can see all these three
different test cases um are testing
different values for different fields
and these are based on different
scenarios which we want to test okay so
this is the way we design our test cases
so we design as many number of test
cases which are required and then we
select all the different values which
are also required here
okay now this is the manual way of
creating test case instances but there
is also automatic way of creating
instances and this is provided by
tosa so and uh TOS also provides you
different methods through which you can
create these different combinations of
test case instances so these are known
as combinatorial methods in tosa and
generally there are four combinatorial
methods
okay so let's look at them I'm going to
delete this instances now uh you can
directly select and delete here and then
when you right click on this test sheet
and you go to generate instances okay so
these are all the different options as I
said there are four different options
one is um a extension of this particular
uh option which is uses the relation
concept but uh to say there are four
different combinations which you can
create okay so let's go through them
quickly um so the first one is all
combinations now this is uh as the name
suggest it creates uh test case
instances uh considering all the
different combinations so it is it will
cover everything all your test data
which you have defined all your
instances and attributes so it will
generate the highest number of test
cases possible
okay so if I uh click here you can see
uh currently it has generated these two
because I have just got uh I mean the
maximum number of instances I have got
is two here and that is why it has
generated only two test
cases um let me do one thing let
me have some more values here so that we
can see uh when it generates more number
of instances so as a said earlier right
we can
also generate our attributes by dragging
the module itself so now you see I
dragged the module and automatically it
created all the different attributes and
also their instances so I have from the
application I have got all the different
values which I can test with so you
don't need to necessarily um create them
manually you can do it automatically
just drag the module into the test sheet
and it will create everything thing here
you might need to modify some things
like for performance you know these are
not the values so we have to modify some
of the values
here okay but uh this will help you to
quickly create um some attributes and
instances based on your application
right um
then obviously you need to uh again do
the character and position of your
instances and uh change the business
relevance when you're doing this um the
automatic way right now coming back to
our test case generation so if I
generate instances all combinations um
you will see
now okay so here you can see that uh the
instances uh were generated and this
exceeds the limit of 1,000 instances
okay okay so if I look here you will so
this particular limit will be set in
some uh
particular property or the project
properties but uh currently thousand
instances are the maximum number of
instances which can be generated so
that's why that error came up right so
that's uh what is all combinations
generally it is not recommended by
trentis or not recommended to even test
with these number of combinations you
can never complete your testing if you
go with all
combinations um this is a small
application and you can see how many it
it generated 7,000 test cases so think
of a big application and what number of
test cases it will
generate then uh coming to orthogonal
combination so this results in the
lowest number of possible
combinations and um what it uh does it
it selects uh at least one instance
value from each attribute and it
generates a particular combination okay
so if I select orthogonal then uh you
will see it will generate uh some
minimum number of test cases you will
see it has already selected the values
here so what it is doing is for each
test case it is trying to select at
least one instance value in each test
case okay so uh it will ensure that you
at least test with one value from each
attribute or one instance from each
attribute in each of your test case Okay
so that way it will generate the
combination so that's called the
orthogonal
combination uh and then let me delete
this
and then there is pair wise combination
uh again it will generate quite a few
combinations uh what it does it uh
generates a combination based on any two
attributes it creates a pair and then it
creates your combinations okay so you
can see here this also creates quite a
few
instances and uh then coming to the last
one so this is called the linear
expansion and this is the one which is
recommended by tricentis and also widely
used because it the optimum number of
test cases which is required to test
your application and which which will
help you to get the maximum coverage as
well okay um but if I select this you
will see there will an error pop up
because uh this linear expansion cannot
be performed if there is no straight
through instance so you can see we need
to define a straight through instance
for each of the attributes and that is
compulsory when you are trying to
perform a linear expansion
okay so I need to select uh one straight
through instance for each of
my for each of my attribute okay if I
don't have it then uh it will not
perform this particular uh scenario or
this particular
combination okay so let me quickly do
that now there is no um automatic way of
doing this you have to do this
manually either you are doing that um by
dragging your module or you have uh
created them manually doesn't matter but
you need to set this state through
instance at least one for each of your
attribute okay so that you can always go
ahead and use this particular uh
combinatorial
method so now if I go here and I use
linear expansion you will see it will
create the number of instances which are
Optimum so um it is not like it is too
less or too more it is the minimum
number of test cases which you require
to test this all your scenarios okay so
these are all the different combin
methods through which you can generate
your instances automatically not
necessarily creating manually you can
create manually or you can use the
automatic way both ways um are correct
there is nothing wrong or right
right
um now this is uh how you design your
test sheet okay you fill all the values
you have your test sheet
instances now coming to how you
basically then create your test cases
right for that um the next step is to
basically link this test sheet to a test
case Okay so that is that will be in
your blue section uh you will have a
test case which will be testing your
application right um I have created this
test case it just contains that
particular module okay and then
different fields here I haven't filled
any values here um and what you need to
do you cannot directly link your test
sheet to a test case you have to create
a template right because once you have a
template then it will tosa will
automatically generate test cases from
that particular template using your test
design sheet so that is how this
framework works okay um so once you have
designed your test case Okay um and then
you have created your test case with
different test steps what you can do is
you can directly right click here and
convert it into a
template so once you convert it into a
template obviously you cannot execute it
it is just a template okay it is helpful
for Designing purpose if you're using
test case design you should have a test
case template and once you have a test
case template then uh you can link your
template to your test design sheet okay
and how you can do that is uh you just
drag your test design sheet into your
template okay once you do that uh then
when um the template is linked to a
particular test design sheet it is also
known as schema definition okay so if I
uh go to
properties and here you will find the
schema name it is our test sheet name
vehicle data okay uh you can also make
sure by jumping to your schema
definition so there is an option here in
your template jump to schema definition
so it will take you to your testing
design sheet okay and um then you can
also do a check template uh if you are
linking this for the first time then you
should always do it it will tell you if
there are any errors um if uh if your
test design sheets contains some
problems and it will tell you all the
issues which are there in your template
or in your test design sheet and which
you need to look on Okay so once you do
check template and no errors found in
template so which means your template is
linked
correctly what it will also do is once
you link this uh it will also fill the
empty values in your Fields with this
Excel um link okay so this is an
expression which uh is basically it is
selecting a value from the Excel sheet
okay so you can can see here this is the
attribute name and then this is the sub
attribute okay so if uh this will only
happen if your values are empty if you
have filled some predefined values then
it will not happen and in that case what
you have to do either you can write this
expression yourself
manually or uh if you don't want to do
that then the other way around is you
just um drag your particular
attribute into this uh value and then it
will create this expression uh which
means it is using a reference of your
Excel sheet and uh this is the path of
that particular attribute okay so it
will when you generate your instances it
will automatically take one value from
this particular instance okay whatever
you have selected for this particular
test case uh it will select that value
based on this sheet
okay so now our template is ready and it
is linked to a test design sheet the
last step is to instantiate which means
create different test
cases now that you can do by right
clicking and then you will uh get an
option here uh to create template
instance the same option is also
available here which is called
instantiate so once you click on the
that it will ask you whether you want to
start instantiation now and you click on
yes and then you will see uh it will
create a folder with your instances now
the number of instances created is the
same number of instances which are
present in your design sheet okay so the
number of instances which were created
here the same number of test cases will
be created right
here um obviously you can change or
modify the names uh here which are
generated but if you go into each test
case you will see uh each test case is
unique uh depending on which type of
combination you have used uh you will
see that it has selected different
values here right so this way um in once
you have designed your test case you can
then have all your test cases which can
test all your scenarios uh Auto
automatically created by tosa uh you
need to take care of a few things like
linking the test sheet to the template
and then you will have all the different
instances what it does it it saves your
time uh first of all you don't need to
create so many test cases manually uh
everything will be done by tosa once you
have the test design sheet and then
maintenance is also easier because if
there are any changes if you want to
change some values or combinations you
can do do uh it in your test design
sheet okay so if I change something here
and then what I need to do is I just
need to go here and I need to
reinstantiate
instance so that particular change will
be automatically reflected right here in
my test case Okay so this way your
maintenance becomes lot easier um and
then chances of uh making mistakes is
also lesser and then it saves you time
and effort to create uh the number of
test cases for your particular
scenario okay so uh this way you can
create your different uh test cases and
then you can pull it into an execution
folder and um then you can directly
start executing your test cases so
something here like an execution list
you can create a folder here uh for your
vehicle
insurance
and then you create a execution list and
then you can directly pull your test
instance folder right here okay it will
create all your execution entries right
here okay um and then if you want to
have your um instance or test case names
in a particular way you can also go to
your template properties there is
something called instance name okay so I
can put some instance name like it
starts with uh TC okay so while
generating the instance it will consider
this um so if I do something like this
and then I go here and I reinstantiate
okay so now you will see that uh it has
created based on this this particular
naming convention so you can make any
naming convention you want um and you
can generate your particular test cases
in the same
way now the last part uh which uh I will
quickly cover is uh classes which is
also part of test design uh test case
designing section now similar to the
concept of library right where you
create a library and you can reuse uh
these libraries it could be your test
step Library where you have got a
certain number of test steps which you
want to reuse across different test
cases okay in a similar way uh if you
are repeating your attributes multiple
times right so think of a test sheet I
have got uh like I have got created here
vehicle data similarly I have got uh
multiple test sheets and I am repeating
uh all the attribut attributes or some
of the attributes in these test sheets
right so rather than doing that rather
than having multiple test sheets which
are using similar attributes what I can
do is I can create a class um and this
class will contain all my common
attributes so that uh if there is any
change I it will be centralized okay so
it reduces your maintenance and it also
becomes easier to maintain because you
only need to make your changes in your
central class it is very similar to the
concept of library or uh maybe a
function where uh you create a function
and then you reuse that function across
your test cases right so creating a
class is pretty easy um that you can do
it multiple ways um you can create it
manually you go into the folder right
click and then create a class okay uh
this class is is nothing different uh
than a sheet but um the difference is it
is a class and it can be used as a
reference in all the other test sheets
okay so it will contain its own
attributes and instances you can create
them manually the other way around is
you can also create it uh
automatically okay so how you can do
that is um uh either you can create it
from uh the module attributes or you can
also create it from these particular
attributes okay so if I copy
this okay uh or if I drag this attribute
into this particular folder a vehicle
insurance you will see there's an option
create class from attribute or create
structure from attribute okay so if I
choose create class from attribute it it
will automatically create a class for me
called enter vehicle data which has got
all the different attributes and
instances okay so you just need to
select the particular attribute and drag
it into the
folder now once you have this class uh
what you can do is um you can directly
use the reference now so you don't need
to have different attributes and
instances so if I go into this
particular sheet
and I delete all my instances here all
my attributes here and what I will do is
I will just use the class here okay so
in my different sheets um I will have a
reference to my class so this enter
vehicle data is now a reference you
cannot directly make changes here
obviously uh whatever changes you want
to make make it in your class okay and
then um it will be reflected everywhere
so the class can be used at multiple
test sheets across your test design
sheets right so I can directly just drag
the class and make it a reference
here okay so this is a way you can
centrally manage your attributes and
instances in your test design
section so yes these are all the
concepts uh which are present in the
test case design section uh you can you
can make use of all these Concepts while
designing your scenarios while
generating your instances or while
generating your different test cases
based on different
scenarios there are few other things
also there um which I could not cover in
this particular session but these are
all the Core Concepts uh on which the
test case designing is built upon and it
is very important um when you are trying
to design your test cases U because it
it reflects that you are trying to use
the complete framework of tosa and not
just using tosa as a tool which can just
create your test cases and execute it
but you are utilizing all the different
components of tosa and this is also a
very common question uh which comes up
uh in your tosa interviews so they ask
you um how do you go ahead and build
your test cases now some candidates will
say that I create a test case directly
in the blue section um where I scan the
module and then I add the test steps but
the better way of saying is uh I start
with the test case designing section
where I design my scenario based on some
technique and then I go ahead and build
a template and then I build my test
cases based on that
and that is a more Optimum way of uh
building your test cases also it gives
you better risk coverage and also better
coverage overall coverage across your
test cases or your
scenarios if there are any questions you
can always uh there are various channels
uh through which you can reach me um you
can directly U send your questions
through email or you can send me through
uh WhatsApp or just uh if you are part
of uh the course then you can also leave
it in the community
section um if you you if you have
already enrolled for the course you
should be already aware of all these
Concepts but uh do let me know if you
have got any other
questions okay um so that's it for
today's session um we will try to have
these sessions more often on different
topics in tosa so do look out for
upcoming webinars on on various topics
within tosa I will try to cover um
topics which are mostly asked by people
uh some server related topics uh in the
coming up weeks
so thanks for joining um and have a good
day and uh we'll speak soon